Onyedikachi Benjamin Ogbonna

Software Engineer

PROFILE

Energetic and passionate, with strong drive for innovations, and 4+ years' experience in software development. With a special interest in Artificial Intelligence, I have excellent understanding and proficiency in building models to solve complex problems. I am eager to obtain a challenging position that will expand my learning and build my skills. I can work effectively with minimal supervision and I'm also an excellent team player, and I desire to learn more about different aspects my industry to further my efficiency in my field.

SKILLS/COMPETENCE

Programming: Python, JavaScript, PHP, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), HTML, CSS, Git, AWS, etc. **Libraries/Framework:** Django, Django Rest, Bootstrap, Tensorflow/Keras, Scikit-learn, etc.

Relevant Courses: Algebra, Calculus, Probability and Statistics.

Soft Skills: Leadership, Excellent Team Player, Excellent Communication, Time Management,

Problem Solving and Goal Oriented.

Volunteering: GDSC, Django Girls, Python weekend, Pie & Al.

EXPERIENCE

2022 - Date Cheaper Ltd: Team Lead/Backend Developer

• Designed and developed a dynamic social commerce application to connect buyers to businesses/sellers near them.

2022 University of Abuja Health Services: Software Developer

 Designed and developed web app using Django, thereby increasing efficiency by 75%.

2021 – 2022 Google Developer Student Clubs: Lead

Host workshops, Training/coding sessions.

Organize tech events (Devfest, Techfest, etc.)

2021 Aspilos Foundation: Project Officer

 Coached/trained over 30 developers on Web development and Data science/ Machine learning.

Supervised the start and completion of projects and addressed complex issues.

PROJECTS

2023 Intl. Research & Development Conference: Kampala Intl. University, Uganda

Presented a paper on "detecting plant disease using CNN".

2022 African Journal of Agriculture & Allied Sciences: Plant Disease Detection

2022 Drowsiness/Sleep Detection System

EDUCATION

2019 – 2023 B.Sc. Computer Science, University of Abuja, Nigeria

2020/2021 Machine Learning: Coursera

PERSONAL INFO

Address:

Area 10 Garki, Abuja, Nigeria.

1 +2348129944424

Portfolio

GitHub

LinkedIn

Hobbies:

- Reading
- Music (Piano)